人人影视
原创翻译  双语字幕
字幕组招新中
请访问 YYSubs.com
翻译    苏葵
校对    苏葵
时间轴    格瑞特
后期    渔夫
总监    苏葵
听我说  拜托  拜托  我能证明
Listen to me, please. Please, I can prove it...
不  不  我能证明  拜托  克里斯申
No! No, I can prove it. Please, Christian -
听我说  拜托
someone listen to me, please!
不不  不要
No, no, please!
我能证明  达沃  听我说
I can prove it. Davor, listen to me!
拜托  不要
Please, no!
你有一条新消息
You have one new message.
我不会放弃你  克里斯申
I won't give up on you, Christian.
您拨打的电话暂时无人接听
This person cannot be reached at the moment.
请在哔声后留言
Please leave a message after the tone.
克里斯申来电
克里斯申未接来电
在我们死之前
第五集
你能来这里吗
Should you even be here?
我依然是你母亲
I'm still your mother.
你不该去工作吗
Shouldn't you be at work?
-克里斯申  -我请病假了
- Christian? - I called in sick.
你病了吗
And are you?
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
那场景一直在我脑海里重复
It's playing in my head on a loop.
一直...挥之不去
It's just...there.
循环不停
All the time.
我永远都无法摆脱这噩梦了
I'll never be able to get away from it.
你会的
You will.
你会的  你会的
You will, you will.
你...
You've...
你只需要多给点时间
You've just got to give it time.
我觉得我撑不下去了
I don't think I can handle it.
我不该承受这些
You shouldn't have to.
这一切  都不怪你
All this, you're not to blame.
这是我的烂摊子  不是你的
This is my fuck-up, not yours.
我...
I've...
我犯了好多错
I've made so many mistakes.
对你爸爸
With your dad,
对你
with you.
肖恩
Sean.
我们都不对彼此说真话
None of us ever really speaking the truth to one another.
我很抱歉要由你
And I'm so fucking sorry because you're the one
来承担后果
that's paid the price.
但除了杀死斯特凡外还有什么选择
But what was the alternative to killing Stefan?
你自己死吗
Your own death?
你选择了生存
You are hard wired to survive,
你也活了下来
and you did.
杀死斯特凡是正确的事
Killing Stefan was the right thing to do.
我知道你为此付出了很大代价
Now, I know that it's come at a terrible cost.
但那个代价会让你成为
But that cost will make you
一个坚强智慧的男人
a strong and a wise man.
你会挺过去
You will get through this.
你从哪拿到这个的
Where did you get this?
肖恩在我坐牢时给我的
Sean gave it to me when I was in prison.
他说这能保护我安全
He said it was to keep me safe.
应该给你
You should take it.
不  不要
No, no way.
给我戴太不精致了
That's got a bit of work to do yet.
是时候做决定了
It's time to decide.
你干还是不干
Are you in or are you out?
着什么急
What's the rush?
克拉伊纳已经开始了
Krajina has started.
船定好出发日期了
The ship has set sail?
几小时前离开了安特卫普
It left Antwerp a couple of hours ago,
船上装了特殊的货物
with a very special cargo on board.
那你需要我们干什么
So what do you need from us?
一个简单的答案
A simple answer.
我们要做朋友  一起赚大钱
Are we going to be friends and make money together...
还是做敌人  摧毁彼此
..Or enemies, tear each other apart?
我不会再问第二次
I won't ask again.
我们加入
We're in.
为此敬一杯吧
And let's drink to that.
克里斯申
Christian?
碧昂卡
Bianca...
碧昂卡  拜托  你为什么不接电话
Bianca, please, why won't you answer my calls?
别烦我
Leave me alone.
-什么  -别烦我
- What? - Leave me alone.
我们为什么不能谈谈
Why can't we just talk?
我不想跟你说话
I don't want to speak with you.
你说过不会放弃我
You said you wouldn't give up on me.
-碧昂卡  -离我远点  克里斯申
- Bianca... - Stay away from me, Christian.
我知道你干了什么
I know what you did.
这太令人厌烦了
This is getting tiresome.
对我们都是
For all of us.
再说一次  我郑重申明  你没有任何证据
Once again, for the record, you have no evidence to
显示我的当事人与找回的武器有关
link my client to the weapon that was recovered.
除了枪是在他车库里找到的
Except that it was found in his garage.
卡巴夏先生坚称你们不会
Mr Kabashi is adamant you won't
在武器上找到他的DNA
find any of his DNA on the weapon.
你肯定知道我们是来真的  安德里
You must know the game's up, Andri.
还是说你太蠢意识不到这点
Or are you too dumb to realise it?
我们了解你的一切
We know everything about you.
我们知道你的帮派
We know who you associate with,
你的供货人  还有你的客户
who supplies you and who you deal to.
我们知道你的藏匿屋
We know where you keep your stash.
我们知道莉安的一切
We know all about Leanne
她在你的行动里扮演什么角色
and the part she plays in your operation.
弗洛里安还太小  不该被送入领养院
Florian's very young to be taken into care.
我再问一次
For the record,
你杀了肖恩·哈达克吗
did you shoot Sean Hardacre?
问询结束  11点45分
Interview terminated, 11:45.
我快好了
I'm nearly finished.
不着急
No rush.
好奇怪
That's weird.
什么
What's that?
那个女人
That woman.
她吗
Her?
她是谁
Who is she?
斯特凡·瓦盖奇的已知同伙
Known associate of Stefan Vargic.
谁
Who?
树林里的那个男尸
The guy found up in the woods.
真的吗  你确定吗
Really? Are you sure?
很确定
Pretty sure.
为什么这么问
Why do you ask?
她上周来过警局
She came to the station last week.
说她担心自己失踪的男友
Said she was worried about her missing boyfriend.
我们让她做了部分身份信息验证
We got her to do a partial ID.
斯特凡·瓦盖奇吗
Stefan Vargic?
她发誓不是他
She swore blind it wasn't him.
碧昂卡
Bianca?
怎么了
Yeah?
我是芙兰·希利  你有空吗
Fran Healy. Do you have a moment?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只想谈谈
I just wanna talk.
我知道是你帮助我们确认了斯特凡
I know it was you who helped us to identify Stefan.
那肯定需要很大的勇气
That must have taken a lot of nerve.
他死了
The fact that he's dead...
让人感觉不真实
..It's just so surreal.
你为什么坦白
Why did you come forward?
我只想让这停下
I just want it to stop.
你想让谁停下
You want who to stop?
你的家人吗
Your family?
-你是说他们杀了...  -我什么也没说
- Are you saying they killed... - I'm not saying anything.
你知道任何关于肖恩·哈达克谋杀案的事吗
Do you know anything about the murder of Sean Hardacre?
我得走了
I have to go.
我能帮你  碧昂卡
I can help you, Bianca.
让一切停下
To make it stop...
克里斯申
Christian?
克里斯
Chrissy?
我给你买了咖喱  你就不用做饭了
I brought you a curry so that you don't need to cook.
克里斯申
Christian?
克里斯申  天呐  醒醒  醒醒
Christian, come on, wake up, wake up.
好吧
Ok...
紧急情况  你需要什么服务
Emergency. What service do you require?
救护车
Ambulance, please.
地址是哪里
What's the address?
斯托克斯克罗夫特  格洛斯特法院14B
It's 14B, Gloucester Court, Stokes Croft.
你来电的原因是什么
What's the reason for your call?
我儿子  他昏迷了
Yes, it's my son. He's unconscious.
我觉得他
I-I think he's, ah...
我觉得他吃了药  喝了酒
I think he's taken some pills and, erm, alcohol.
但我不知道是什么  和服用的剂量
I don't know what and I don't know how much.
他多大了
How old is he?
24岁
He's 24.
他有呼吸吗
Is he breathing?
对  他有呼吸
Yes, he's breathing.
我检查了他的呼吸道  他还有呼吸
I checked his airways and he's breathing.
请保持冷静  救护车马上到
Please stay calm. An ambulance is on its way.
克里斯申  挺住
Christian, come on...
他怎么样了
How is he?
醒了  但很虚弱
Awake but very weak.
他说什么了吗
Has he said anything?
他说是个意外
He claims it was an accident.
医生似乎相信他
The doctors seem to believe him
但他们给他提供了心理咨询  以防万一
but they offered him counselling just in case.
我暂时相信他吧
Well, I'll give him the benefit of the doubt.
他还活着  这最重要
He's alive, that's the main thing.
船已经离港了
The ship's left port.
什么时候到港
When will it dock?
后天  如果是往布里斯托开的话
Day after tomorrow, assuming it's heading for Bristol,
但我们不能确定
although we can't be sure of anything.
没有克里斯申的话
Without Christian.
我本来打算说没有更多情报的话
I was going to say without further intelligence
但其实是一回事
but it amounts to the same thing.
我得回他身边了
I'd better get back to him.
好
Ok.
你保重
You take care.
碧昂卡
碧昂卡  拜托
你为什么不接电话
我不知道你觉得自己知道什么  我们能谈谈吗
碧昂卡  见鬼
求你了
我快疯了
接电话吧
你说过不会放弃我
拜托  碧昂卡
我们再也不交谈了
We never talk any more.
-我们一直谈话啊  -但不谈心了
- We talk all the time. - Not properly.
跟我说说  怎么了
Speak to me. What's wrong?
你在想斯特凡吗
Are you thinking about Stefan?
你不必担心
You mustn't worry.
我们昨晚接到了他的电话  他没事
We heard from him last night. He's doing fine.
至于你
And as for you...
这个嘛
..Well...
男人们很快会排着长队
..They're going to be queuing up
等着跟你约会  我美丽的女儿
to date you, my beautiful baby girl.
好了
Now...
开心点  宝贝
..Be happy, duso.
我们不能让你在我的生日会上
We can't have you making everyone
把大家惹得不开心
miserable at my birthday party.
克拉伊纳
Krajina.
来啊
Come on!
现身吧
Show yourselves!
你这懦夫
You fucking cowards!
我觉得不用把这个放回去了
Hardly seems worth putting back.
真神奇  竟然在这么小的玻璃里
It's amazing how much they can put away
放了这么多液体
in these tiny little glasses.
你在干什么
What on earth are you doing?!
我自己出院了
I've discharged myself.
你说真的吗
You can't be serious?
我要去找人谈谈
I'm going to go and speak to someone.
你在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
他们做什么都不能阻止我
There's nothing they can do to stop me.
克里斯申  你就不能
Christian, can't you at least talk
-跟那里的人谈谈吗  -说什么
- to someone in there? - And say what?
我该告诉他们什么
What am I going to tell them?
别担心我了  我没事
Just stop worrying about me. I'm fine.
我得回去了
I have to get back.
-我不会让你回去  -妈  住手
- I'm not going to let you. - Mum, stop it!
我得结束这一切
I have to finish this.
对  我想从现在起
Yes, I can assure you you won't need
你不需要找别人了
to go to anyone else from now on.
好  听着  我们晚点说  好吗  拜
OK, listen, erm, we'll talk later, OK? Bye.
怎么了
What happened?
他们认为我癫痫发作了
They think I had a seizure.
-什么  -很轻微
- What? - It was a minor one.
-我现在没事了  -你之前有过吗
- I'm fine now. - Have you had it before?
是怎么引起的
So...what brought it on?
医生认为是压力导致
They think it's stress related.
-好吧  听着  你要休息一阵  -不  不行
- OK, listen, you're going to take some time off. - No, no way.
我们在克罗地亚有房子
We have a place in Croatia you can use.
我们就快结束了  我想参与
We're almost done. I want to be part of it.
听着  这里没有你能做的事了
Listen, there is nothing for you to do here.
-那货物呢  -兹沃诺密尔去就行了
- What about the consignment? - Zvonomir will meet it.
这活一人干就够了
It's one man job.
你决定在哪接头了吗
Have you decided where?
如果我告诉你  就得杀了你
Now, if I told you that, I'd have to kill you.
你联系这个人
This is who you contact.
告诉他我承认
Tell him I will play ball.
但除非我得到保证
But only if I get a guarantee that
我家人会被妥善照顾
my family will be taken care of.
什么保证
What kind of guarantee?
我们是说话算话的人
We're men of our words.
打电话给达沃就行
Just make the call to Davor.
时间正好
但跟你母亲的生日会撞上了
我觉得正好
我不明白
所有人都会在这里  举杯庆祝过去
方圆百英里内所有克罗地亚人
而你可以骑着摩托车溜出去锁定我们的未来
我没这么想过
我们最大的一批货物
比我们之前做的所有交易都值钱
那就值得庆祝
所以克里斯申不会参与交易
So Christian won't be involved with the exchange?
对  我们认为不会
No, we don't think so.
我们也没法追踪潜艇的位置
And we've no way of tracking the sub?
很不幸  是的
Unfortunately, no.
那我们就不知道这些货物会在哪交易
Then we've no idea where the goods will come ashore.
但我们知道大概的时间
But we know roughly when.
我们也知道谁要去交易
And we do know who's going to meet them.
如果我们能追踪他  他就能带我们到接头点
If we can track him, then he should lead us to the drop off.
好  那我们要怎么做
OK, so how do we do that?
我们睁一只眼闭一只眼  让克里斯申自己行动
We turn a blind eye and allow Christian to use his initiative.
他到目前为止干得很好
He's done all right so far.
听着  现在该告诉凯恩吗
Look, is this the moment to brief Kane?
最好的情况  我们被文件缠身  结果太迟
At best we get drowned in paperwork and we're too slow.
最差他叫停整个项目
At worst he shuts the whole thing down.
我们就失去了把所有事联系到一起的机会
And we lose our chance to tie the whole thing together.
我们需要枪支
We'll need firearms clearance.
你有行动权限
You have operational authority.
还有后援
And back up.
你不认为我们能搞定吗
You don't think we can handle this?
我们不知道对方是什么人
We've no idea what we'll be up against.
不如告诉芙兰  还有马库斯
What about looping in Fran? Marcus?
太冒险了
It's too risky.
我认识一个人
There's someone I know.
我不敢问
I daren't ask.
你最好别问
It's better if you don't.
是有人被折磨的录像吗
Was it footage of someone being tortured?
我只看了一小会
I only saw it for a second.
你能...
Will you...
拷贝下来吗
..Copy it?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果你不帮我  我也无法帮你
I can't help you if you don't help me.
谢谢
Thank you.
你说过你有照片
And you said you had some photos?
对
Yeah.
稍等
Hold on.
这是我哥哥达沃
That's my brother Davor.
这是我妈妈
Erm, that's my mum.
你可以忽略那个
Oh, you can ignore that one.
-你认识这个女人吗  -对  她是朋友的母亲
- You know this woman? - Yeah, she's a mum of a friend.
但她与此事无关
She's not involved.
你能发给我吗
Will you send me those?
好
Yeah.
我的当事人想提供口供  供记录在案
My client wishes to make a statement for the record.
我想招供
I want to confess.
杀了那个警察
To killing that cop.
肖恩·哈迪克吗
Sean Hardacre?
我没问他的名字
I didn't ask his name.
你能告诉我们发生了什么吗
Will you tell us what happened?
我知道他在调查我们
I knew he was keeping tabs on us.
不是你
Not you.
你怎么知道的
How did you know that?
我不记得了
I... I don't remember.
或许我们该让卡巴夏先生
Perhaps we might let Mr Kabashi
把他的口供说完
get to the end of his statement?
我给了他一个消息
I fed him a tip off,
把他引诱到荒无人烟的地方
lured him to a remote spot.
接着说
Go on.
本来计划打他一顿
The plan was to rough him up.
找出他对我们知道多少
Find out how much he knew.
然后呢
And?
他逃了
He escaped.
显然他知道了我的长相
It was obvious he could identify me.
所以我得杀了他
So I had to kill him.
那迈克·弗雷斯特呢
And Michael Forrester?
那个农民
The farmer.
随便谁吧
Whatever you say.
有证据显示这些凶案
There's evidence that may link these murders
与斯特凡·瓦盖奇的谋杀有关
to the killing of Stefan Vargic.
安德里·卡巴夏招供了肖恩的谋杀
Andri Kabashi has confessed to Sean's murder.
真是操蛋
What a crock of shite!
他有可能在说实话吗
Is there any chance he's telling the truth?
不  全是胡说
No. It's total bollocks.
但我们没有证据
But we don't have evidence
把米密查家族和肖恩的谋杀联系到一起
that connects the Mimicas to Sean's murder.
你自己也说了
You said it yourself.
肖恩在调查米密查家族
Sean was investigating the Mimicas,
不是什么安德里·卡巴夏
not Andri fucking Kabashi!
我们知道他们有联系
We know they have links.
或许肖恩也有安德里的情报
Maybe Sean had intel on Andri, too.
卡巴夏只是个小喽啰
Kabashi is a total nobody.
他没有别人允许都不敢给自己擦屁股
He can't even wipe his backside without someone's permission!
我们在他车库找到了俄罗斯特种部队手枪
Well, we found a Russian Special Forces revolver in his garage.
-真方便  -而且他还招供了
- Oh, how convenient! - And he happens to have confessed.
-有人抢先说服了他  -有人抢先说服了谁
- Someone got to him! - Someone's got to whom?
我的一个线人  长官
A contact of mine, sir.
我们在说其他的案子  长官
We were talking about another investigation, Sir.
你走运了
You got lucky.
-人得给自己制造运气  -不是这个案子
- You make your own luck, sir. - Not in this case.
很遗憾你这么想
I'm sorry you think that.
我想要你团队调查的
I want a full account of every line of inquiry
所有线索的详细报告  周五之前放我桌上
your team's been following on my desk by Friday.
-周五  -最好是正经报告
- Friday? - And it better be good.
你好吗
Hi. How are you?
你看起来糟透了
You look terrible.
他们在医院里说  你...
They said at the hospital, you...
我不想谈
I don't wanna talk about it.
听着  我有些坏消息
Listen, erm, I'm afraid that I've got some bad news.
安德里·卡巴夏供认杀了肖恩
Andri Kabashi confessed to killing Sean.
安德里
Andri?
对  他们在他车库找到了凶器
Yeah, they found the murder weapon in his garage.
你相信他吗
And you believe him?
老大相信  这才是最重要的
Well, the top brass do, and that's all that matters.
等等  如果安德里被起诉了
Wait, if Andri's being charged...
他死了
He's dead.
他的牢房里有刀片
A razor blade in his prison cell.
-他们让他背锅了  -对
- They got to him. - Yeah.
所以他们不会为肖恩的凶案坐牢吗
So they won't get done for killing Sean?
我可能因谋杀坐牢  但他们却不会
I could serve time for murder, but they won't?
克里斯申
Christian,
斯特凡被枪击了三次
Stefan was shot three times.
很可能不是你杀了他
It's highly probable that you didn't kill him.
我们得继续
We have to keep going.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
我们抓他们现行
We catch them in the act.
怎么做
How?
我还有船上的追踪器
I still have one of the trackers from the boat.
妈妈
Mum?
怎么了
What?
又一盆植物
It's another plant.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do with it.
老天啊
Mother of God.
克里斯申  你能帮帮碧昂卡吗
Christian, can you help Bianca, please?
放到露台上
On the terrace.
把那画摘掉
Take that down.
达沃让我挂这里
Davor told me to hang it here.
我是六十岁  不是八十  拿下来
I'm 60, not 80 . Take it down.
妈妈  蛋糕来了
Ah, Mum, the cakes.
放到地下室的储藏柜里
Ah, in the storage cupboard in the basement.
克里斯申  我们需要更多酒
Christian, we need more wine.
跟我来
Follow me.
把那画一起拿上
And bring that with you.
跟上  克里斯申
Keep up, Christian.
真遗憾你母亲不能来
It's such a pity your mother can't come.
我们对他还有其他了解吗
Do we know any more about him?
听说他们一起在波斯尼亚服过役
They served together in Bosnia, apparently.
但他是...警察吗
But is he...police?
干得好
Well done, you.
还有什么
What else do we have?
这装备真不错
That's a great piece of kit.
你感觉如何
How are you feeling?
谢天谢地我们终于
Thankful that we've finally got
有好机会抓住他们了
a decent shot at nailing them.
-扎拉特科  -杜布拉芙卡
- Zlatko, ah! - Dubravka!
请进
Come in.
-齐瓦娜  -杜布拉芙卡
- Zivana! - Dubravka.
-碧昂卡  -请进  请进
- Bianca! - Come in, come in!
你长大了
You have grown.
你不能现在逃跑
You can't escape now.
我得去继续打扮
I need to finish getting ready.
你看着美极了
You look amazing.
好了
Now...
你去多拿点酒
..You go and get more drinks.
让大家都有酒
Organise them.
好好享受
Enjoy.
听着  我们香槟不够了
Listen, ah, we're running low on champagne.
你先让我拿一些来吗
You want me to fetch some more?
对  拿一箱  再拿一瓶佩林科瓦克
Yeah, get a case, and get a bottle of Pelinkovac.
在门边的柜子上
Ah, on the cupboard by the door.
有信号了
We've got a signal.
当我们刚来这里时  大概是
When we first came here, more than...
天呐  25年前了  我们一无所有
Ah, God, 25 years ago, we had nothing.
我们刚失去了房子  生意
We'd lost our home, our business.
我们失去了我父亲  马克
And we lost my father, Marco.
但你不是过来哀悼  妈妈
But you didn't come here to mourn, Mama.
你过来为我们所有人建立了更好的生活
You came here to build a better life for all of us.
而且从那时起你就为了这个目标努力工作
And you've worked so hard to achieve that ever since,
日夜不停
day and night.
我很荣幸跟大家一起分享..
It's so great that we can share...
齐瓦娜  你给妈妈找了第一份工作
Zivana, you found Mama her first job,
打扫手术室
cleaning at the surgery.
扎拉特科  你借给她钱
And, Zlatko, you lent her the money
开了我们第一家餐厅
to open our first restaurant.
布里斯托最小的披萨店
the smallest pizzeria in Bristol!
我们能有今天  要感谢你的努力工作  妈妈
We're here today thanks to your hard work, Mama,
但也要感谢你们  我们亲爱的朋友
but also thanks to you, our dear friends.
小家伙
Hi, sweetie.
今天是特别的一天
Today is a very special day.
敬你  我最亲爱的妈妈
A toast to you, dearest Mama.
干杯
Zivjeli!
*祝你生日快乐*
*Happy birthday to you*
*祝你生日快乐  杜布拉芙卡*
*Happy birthday, Dubravka!*
*祝你生日快乐*
*Happy birthday to you.*
碧昂卡在哪
Where's Bianca?
我来了  妈妈
I'm here, Mama.
谢谢  谢谢大家
Thank you. Thank you.
看上去该行动了
Looks like we're on.
他们出发了
They're on the move.
你在实战中开过枪吗
You ever fired one when it counts?
你一会还要看我的持枪执照吗
You'll be asking to see my certificates next.
只想确认你不会给我背后来一枪
Just checking you're not gonna shoot me in the back.
别诱惑我  比利
Don't fucking tempt me, Billy.
你们还需要什么的话
Anything else you want...
他会照顾你们
He will look after you.
你知道今天要弹什么吗
And do you know what you're going to play today?
一切都好吗
Everything all right?
嗯
Yeah.
他还在往西南方向走
He's still heading south-west.
他离我们多远
How far ahead is he?
几英里
It's a couple of miles.
他转弯了
He's turning off.
去海边
Heading for the coast.
名字  我们需要名字  告诉我名字
A name, we need name! Give me name!
谁是内鬼  快说  谁是内鬼
Who is mole? Come on, who is mole?
名字  我们需要名字
A name, we need name!
够近了
This is close enough.
坐下
Sit.
你得看这个
You have to watch this.
按播放
Press play.
克里斯申
Christian!
我的线人是克里斯申
My source is Christian.
克里斯申是我的线人
Christian is my source.
克里斯申
Christian.